All right. Thank you for coming.
Really cool session coming up just now.
We've got Peter Wilson and Davide Eynard.
They are going to be talking to you about CQ Stack Overflow for agents.
I don't know if you've seen contributions to human.
Stack overflow basically plummeted
after ChatGPT came out, which is really sad for all of us.
Hopefully these two can do something about it.
Give them a round of applause, please.
Take it away.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Very one.
So I'm David. He's Peter.
We're both from Mozilla.ai.
The first thing I wanted to start with was Mozilla.
Because the first thing they usually people tell us
is, are you the Firefox guys or are you the browser guys?
We don't want the AI in the browser and things like that.
Or we're very happy to have AI the browser.
This doesn't happen that often though.
So I left an exercise for you for after the talk.
If you have the Firefox application installed on your laptops,
try and connect to moz://a.
This is kind of a Fakhri, but the browser folks can do anything they want with it.
So you just connect to that and it will open the Mozilla manifesto,
which is a manifesto that has been set up like 20 years ago when the internet was
at, let's say it's very beginning, at least from the user perspective.
It kind of began even 25 more, more years earlier.
So in that manifesto, you find some principles
that are all about the internet, the web as a resource that was open,
that should have remained open and they should have, and
where people should be able to drive the experience they have of the web,
where security is important and were open code
and the standards and interoperability are very important.
So the next step in the exercise is your play a regular expression.
And you substitute the internet with AI and try and see
if this makes sense to you.
And I did this exercise before applying for Mozilla AI, and I was mind blown
at how actual this principle could be, even if you just moved the internet to AI.
And this is exactly the same exercise that the Mozilla Foundation folks
did a few years ago.
It's five years ago, before the big AI boom, when they decided they wanted
to fund a startup company to work on AI, not specifically in the browser.
So something separate from the Mozilla Corporation working on Fifo,
but something that was only directed towards promoting open source AI.
So it's as we are not the browser guys, we love the browser
guys, we talk to them, we are siblings, we are just focusing on open source AI.
So first thing when you talk about open source AI is a comparison.
I see done very often in terms of user experience.
Very often people take open weights models and then try and evaluate them
and see how they work for their tasks and then compare them to commercial
AI services.
But what often they don't think about is that a commercial AI service
is not just an LLM, it's an agent code plus tools, plus engineering,
plus thousands of engineers working on more engineering.
And to me, the comparison is a bit unfair and creates a gap between the perception
that users have of close AI services versus open source AI.
So our mandate is to try and make this gap smaller, but making OpenAI,
sorry, open source AI more accessible to users and something
where their experience is very similar to the one of commercial services.
The first thing
we want to work on or we want to talk about is context.
And here I have two very simple examples.
If you are here, you probably all know that context is king and context
is important and it's important, but from the bad or negative point of view
and from the positive point of view, this is the negative example.
We have a tool that's called agents that allows you
to play with agents in your browser, connecting to a local LLM.
And one problem we gave
it was try and connect to this website, which is the Mozilla AI.
I think it was the any-agent repository.
Yes, the any-agent project and tell us how many stars it has.
And the first times I tried this tool I was like, man, I did something wrong
because it's just returning me the manual to any agent.
What's happening and what I realized later.
At the time, I was still using the default context size was 4K,
and my tool was downloading stuff from the web and getting way more tokens
that were available in the context that was made available by alarm.
So at the time, the full choice for K nothing shown because logs
were not apparent to the user.
Usually great user experience because if you have a very small context size,
the LM is going to work on your system, but the context is cut.
The model forgets the the question that it's been asked,
and it will just take the page and summarize it to you to some extent.
So this is the bad example.
A good example instead is this one.
We were playing with any agent,
which is another open source tool that we're building.
And we were trying to answer simple questions.
I very much like naive, super simple examples.
This one is about my birthday.
I asked Claude what my birthday was and he said, oh, I don't know this David.
I asked what my name was.
It was a bit harsher.
It said David, I didn't know, but it doesn't appear anywhere,
so I cannot really tell his birthday.
And then I tried to add a tool, a very simple one that had two functions.
It was browse this directory and open and read the contents of this file,
and then ask the same question to a local small model that kind of try
to open stuff and found a birthday file and then opened it.
Found that there were birthdays of very popular computer scientists.
You can see there's other Lovelace, Alan Turing and Charles
Babbage and me, and it answered properly.
And the nice thing is,
this is a positive example from a model that 0.8 billion large.
And again, you already know this.
You inject the proper context and the thing is going to work better
even than a commercial model to some extent.
Then, to be completely truthful, the zero 8 billion models took quite some attempts
to get this done properly, but still with very small local models.
Let's say for billions, nine billions you will see them.
This is not right.
This is a local agent answering your questions.
You will see it trying to open the directory,
seal the files, try and get a sense of what's there.
See there something called birthdays and detect that birthdays is a good file
name for something that might contain date words and automatically open this.
So we are
living in the context world
and something that we feel we are kind of missing from our contexts
is ways to solve issues
that the models have not experienced yet.
So this is a very frequent use case.
You have an LLM, you have a or a commercial model to.
In this case it was run with a cloud.
You ask it to solve a problem.
The model finds an issue.
Luckily it's an agent.
It will try and fix the issue, try other solutions.
But in some cases the solution is just not there.
It won't be able to find it unless you interrupt it and say, you know,
this thing should be done differently.
It will do the thing differently and from then on continue without any,
any problem.
So what if you could save this information and reuse it to some extent?
And I think Claude does this already.
It has memories.
And you might think that Claude probably is everything that you need to solve
this task.
I'm going to hand this out to Peter,
because he had a nice experience with Claude to tell you.
Yeah, I'm very good friends with Claude.
Here's an empty slide.
Yeah.
So, like David said, folks might say, yeah, but we've got agents MD and Claude.
We can just add rules and that solves it.
Or if you debunk that slightly, then
you say, oh, well, we've got memories now as well, so that will solve it. But
I've,
I've got enjoyed quite a lot of time with you in two seconds.
I'll keep that off the side for now.
But I guess the problem with that is that one, it's all it's stored locally.
You end up with everything stored in like a Claude.md file.
I mean, you can have your global one and you have a project one,
but all of that stuff
then also has to get loaded
into the context, which also means
that Anthropic and friends get to see what's in your context.
So you might not want all that stuff getting send up there.
So yeah, the memories thing
I feel like was intended to kind of like improve on the rules.
But sometimes, even with memory, Claude seems a little bit forgetful.
So I asked it click this question, which was saying, basically,
can you just go and have a little spy at all
these memory files you'd been writing and see,
like if there's basically duplication across them?
And Claude was very happy
and obliging and told me I was great and then came back and said,
yeah, nothing's the same, basically, because they're not byte identical
and they don't have the same file name, so they just must be completely different.
And I was like,
are you kind of took me a little bit too literally there, so past it, you know,
with a little bit of steering, maybe just check for the intent.
And then Claude on the wind did lots of things and then came back
and till the obvious that he said, oh, yeah, I've been writing the same memory
tons of times in different places and also just ignoring it.
So a little bit.
Yeah. I feel like this was a little bit of a therapy session.
So I will also share some things that happened
with me and Claude very quickly, which is to fight this Claude
not following the rules that it's been given and just doing what it wants.
Sometimes even when you say no to a prompt, doing what it wants,
stuff where it remembered things and kept relapsing.
And just once when it just told me it was confused.
So yeah, it's the good times.
Anyway.
So getting back to the topic, I guess CQ, the blog post that we put out
about this initially was describing it as Stack Overflow for agents.
That was a lot to do with me
having a very smooth brain, and it seemed like it made sense.
And disclaimer for this slide,
it doesn't exactly what guy this, but it just try and paint the picture.
But the idea being that you've got your agent running away runs into some errors.
Does that stuff that David
before finally figures out this is how you do this thing.
And then at that point, what it should do in our ideal world is propose.
That is what we call a knowledge unit to CQ.
So we've got CQ exchange at the bottom that if anyone can scan that,
if they want to go and see the
the kind of hosted version that we're running, but also the open
source CQ repo that Mozilla AI's got has got an open source
server component that you can run yourself locally in Docker or whatever.
And just check in the case I forget anything, so don't ever forget anything.
Yeah, that was just it was just a QR code I wasn't supposed to forget.
Okay, cool.
So what was the knowledge unit?
I spoiler alert we don't save them.
We just put them in JSON. But it looks pretty.
Maybe in YAML on a slide.
So the idea being that we have this schema for a knowledge unit,
that the agent's got a skill that explain this in a second how works.
But this is just basically what gets saved when it's run into a problem.
Like what?
Like what the domains were
that it thought it was working in, what the kind of insight was.
So what what like some reads got, what action had to take.
And then it gets like some metadata
so they can save around the languages it was using the frameworks.
It can save a little pattern I think for once as well.
Yeah.
And then this is kind of how it works on the
on the right hand side hits the problem, figures out to fix it.
Summarizes that stuff submitted to CQ when you're running in a remote mode
that gets approved by a human in the loop review took over in a second.
And then once that's been proposed and exists in the server
and has been reviewed than any other agent on the planet,
that's talking to our hosted CQ instance can get that via a query.
So the idea being that the skill itself will say,
before you start working on a new task, you should come query CQ for that domain
and see if there's something that might give you a hand.
So you kind of get like very targeted specific bits of information
rather than having to either load everything on the front
or figure it out, whatever. Yeah.
Okay. Cool. I'm still talking.
I'm going to hand it back to point just to keep it exciting.
So yeah.
So CQ, the skill is basically like a, there's a skill
which you can still plug in and then that runs an MCP server
because you've got to have an MC server to be cool, and then the server
to let you do this so you can query to see what has already got.
Let's see.
You can propose things once you find it, you know, non-obvious problem
that would save another agent time.
Once you once you get something from querying the guidance and the skills
like validate this thing first, don't just blindly use it.
But anyway, once it's checked and then it tries something out and says,
actually that did work, it should confirm it.
So you kind of build up this confidence scoring over time.
And similarly if there's something wrong like it's still guidance
or it's completely wrong, it can flag that thing as well.
There's also a kind of human trigger,
part of the skill in the plugin, which is that
at the end of a session, if you feel like it missed some stuff,
you can ask it to like reflect over the whole session
and kind of show you what it thinks might be like, summarize
knowledge units and then you can like approve them and edit them and stuff.
Yeah.
And so how it works I guess initially is this on the left is when you install
install the plugin by default it's you just kind of
you get like a little SQLite database locally.
So nothing goes anywhere as the default installation.
So anyone can just start using it on your own machine.
And that also means that anything
it creates and proposes is saved there.
There's no like, review process in this stage.
So any other agents are running on that machine automatically.
Just see that stuff straight away.
You can then configure it to connect to a remote tier.
So as mentioned before, you've got an OS server component of the the CQ repo.
And that kind of allows you to do almost have like a team level thing.
So you can add some users with using in passwords
and then everyone can propose them.
And at that point
you have to go through a review process, which I joked yesterday,
looks a little bit like Tinder.
I think it's got a screenshot to show you, but
and then also that there's a public commons,
which is for us, which is like Mozilla, I'm going to say curated.
But, you know, that kind of vibe where when this thing's
fully up and running, the idea is that, you can propose things up
through the chain.
And so if you've got even within your, like, private namespace on the
on exchange, you could actually this is something that applies to everyone.
And I want to nominate that to be graduated up to the Commons.
That's kind of that StackOverflow view of like once it's there
then it's something that everyone can see.
Yeah okay.
But but risks.
So yeah we've got to be honest about a lot of this stuff.
Said StackOverflow a few times.
And with that comes a bit of like,
oh, this feels a little bit like a social network in some ways.
There's a lot of potential
things that could go wrong with this, and we know about them.
We did talk with the security expert.
We've got like an old stride internally.
We've got this document we've tried to look at to ways
to mitigate these things, but we can't completely get rid of everything. So,
yeah, I'm sorry.
It says on the social media platform.
So basically you've got a variety of things
that could potentially go wrong with this.
So the actual coup could contain something that could make it do
something bad or sad times for enterprise.
And maybe there's personal data or something like that in the skill itself.
Again, there's some things on the front like front loaded on the skill,
which are supposed to mean that it was like a vibe check that we be.
So we've built into it now and we worked alongside someone for that,
which is intended to sort of like go through a series of checks
to try and filter out anything ending up in there.
And the protocol always says, I mentioned earlier, that should always validate K
before it tries to actually do what it tells it to do.
Obviously that's front loaded stuff, but there's still potential for other things.
When you look at the server side and the server side of
things like DDoS and identity spoofing and all the other stuff
that comes along with it.
So yeah, we're saying this
you kind of have the same assumptions that given the open internet, that this is
a free commons for everyone, but we have to be careful with that.
I'll stop talking in a second, I promise.
Wrap it up, Peter.
I give another time. Yeah.
So some of the stuff
we've got this idea of mitigation, as we mentioned before,
and some of the kind of the defense in depth is,
you might consider it like, what ways could we go about trying to improve this?
So, with the exchange platform we build in like some of the roadmaps to
at the end about was like we could use cryptographic signing maybe.
So you've got an API key.
So I guess very, very quickly when you sign in to CQ Exchange
or even the open source one, you get like a JWT token for yourself,
but then you can
then create short lived API keys, which you give to your agent,
so that actually
like delegating permission to your to the agent to act on your behalf.
And then we'll take one one step.
But then so you can't do control plane operations with an API key.
And then also the idea being that like that verifies
like who that person was or what that was acting on behalf of.
But then we could do signing of the actual knowledge unit.
You could potentially upload your public key into the
exchange and sort of opt into that sort of stuff.
We can then make sure that it came from your computer as well.
So it's like a layered mitigation there.
There's the idea of like layered
guardrails or guardrails pipeline, where we kind of pass
through a lot of stuff as it comes through.
So you could check for PII, you can check for stuff out.
We could be could run sandboxes for things.
And the human in the loop review stuff is something
that we'd we've talked about internally as well.
At some point, maybe we need to be able to get away from
that to like human on the loop, to be able to scale it much more.
But for now, we're very keen on making sure we do this right.
So we're doing human in the loop reviews for things
before they become available to other people.
And at the same, when you play with this yourself in the server.
Oh, here we go.
There's some screenshots,
so there's the Tinder one you can swipe left and right with that's
on the open source one,
and the CQ Exchange one that we just released last week.
It looks a little bit more sensible, but that's that.
And then I think I can give it back to David a
thank you.
Sorry. Thank you for your time.
So first of all, I need to say we didn't fix it for everyone or forever.
We fixed it for a very specific use case.
That was a very personal one.
I wanted to run the Joplin MCP.
So Joplin is an open source note taking tool, which I've been using since,
I don't know, 15 years ago or something like that.
So it has plenty of nodes
and I want to have my own, let's say LM wiki like experience.
I wanted it to make make it accessible to cloud.
So I just asked Claude, how can I add a new MCP server?
I know the configuration.
I know all the keys I have to add.
How should I do that?
It gave me some instructions.
I followed them and this was beginning of April.
So you will find some things which might not be super up to date
with the latest version of SQL, but they're definitely reflecting
the behavior of cloud.
So Claude tried to install and told me everything is fine.
You have your MCP server set up.
Then I started Claude again and I couldn't find it.
So I asked, what's the problem?
And I said, let me look into that.
And it continued for a while, trying to find more possible causes.
And eventually, after quite some time and tokens,
I decided to give it a suggestion like,
why don't you look for the up to date documentation on your own website?
And this is what Claude did.
It went and checked it out and eventually found a solution
that was like the configuration file has to be in another path
and fixed it and eventually told me, okay, now the problem is fixed.
So what I did with you after that was to explicitly say do, secure, reflect.
So reflect on what happened.
Go through your trace and find how you fix the issue.
And then it created its own knowledge unit.
We proposed it to the system and saved it.
In that case, it was still just a local.
This is why I say we didn't fix it for everyone yet,
because it was on the local setup that we had and once fixed
I could just restart Claude, The MCP was already there.
I just removed everything
and we started the process from scratch just to show that I could try again.
And then Claude Code automatically looked for relevant information in SQL.
It's found the solution to the problem, so it immediately
decided to use the proper configuration file.
So think about these.
I sold it for myself whenever I run the agent.
Again, not just with Joplin, but with other MCPs.
The configuration is going to be the good one, and I save time and tokens on that.
What if now I can share it with my team?
Or with what if I can share it with everyone else?
Like, what is the value that we add to the whole community
of people developing with the eye power tools?
And we want these tools to be in the hands of just one single corporation.
Or do we want these tools to be in the hands of many people,
potentially your own, your own corporation, or your own team?
If you want to be safe and just share the internal knowledge you have,
but possibly also with as a more general commons open to everyone else.
So what we learned.
Yeah. So yeah, it's been fun for a couple of months.
Then we only begin to June today.
Yeah.
So this kind of start we talked about late February
and then started trying to build this thing throughout April and May.
We learned a lot of things, I think.
And the, the interesting stuff I guess here summarized.
So skeletal frames, Tesla vibes.
It's a big fight for attention because we found a lot of issues
on trying to get the skill trigger at the right time,
because we didn't look like using hooks specifically
and just seeing if we could get the LM and the agent to know
when it should do something rather than ever before.
Every single call, for example,
because it's more like when a task starts, not before every call or whatever.
And so that was interesting.
And how you kind of do versioning and all that stuff, it kind of interesting.
It was why we're here. Yes. That was one thing.
We found the privacy for us.
Privacy first was like the right default a lot.
We've been talking a lot internally again about how we could do things
like Web of Trust and how you could sort of like open this thing up and use
like just rely on the protocol itself to do a lot of stuff for you.
Obviously one of the Mozilla Mozilla like principal things around choice
from privacy around the rest of it.
So it was like, how do we kind of make things more opt in?
So from default you can't see who who else who created a specific key.
You and I say opt into something and all that sort of stuff.
But the lesson we learned around that was it
kind of sometimes makes things a bit slower to
to get there, because you're always having to kind of keep
that in your mind when you're saying, we can build it this way, we can do that.
Well, we build it this way a little, enable us to get there later.
So it's like trying to dodge a lot of things.
The thing compounds.
So even if you use it offline, found that the more things it finds, it
actually becomes quite useful.
I did I've done some podcast, no live stream anyway.
Podcast, the live stream things recently where we did a demo
on the kind of initial demo for this thing was, trying to get it to write
some GitHub actions, and it always used to use versions of like two,
two major versions, our day, which might not be terrifying, but
ideally you want it to be accurate and, that sort of thing.
You find that it didn't matter how many times
if you didn't save stuff with CQ, would have still kept doing it
because it just goes off it's trading day and sort of like full Dunning-Kruger.
It claims it knows everything.
And then it's controversial thing at the end of the platform
before protocol thing, it was more of like a mindset thing, I guess.
So it was like, as Mozilla David said, we want to make sure that we're trying to
put something out there in the public domain.
We want to like, have have protocols, have schemas like try and help
steer that stuff. But actually
it's sometimes the way around.
Maybe you need to have a platform first
to be dog food and stuff to see what's like should be in a in a schema.
What doesn't need to go in there yet, what kind of you might want to leave out?
Maybe people might want to customize their own things.
So we want to get to protocols of our platforms,
but we're just trying to make sure that we kind of
we feel like we're doing it right.
I really just wrap this up. Yeah.
And so I think the last thing maybe from me is, I think that
maybe if CQ isn't for you, don't worry if it is, that's awesome.
But it feels like there's a lot of similar conversations
we're having with people that there's a lot of other people in this space as well.
So if we've got it wrong,
a lot of people have got it wrong, which is slightly reassuring.
So yeah.
Oh yeah. Quit the roadmap. Sorry. That was the thing. What was next?
So from a platform perspective on our exchange, we want to build
a kind of tenancy stuff for names for namespaces.
So it's not just individual contributor stuff.
It's all private and working on the nomination graduation pipeline.
So you can graduate stuff from all namespace to commons regardless.
Pipelines I mentioned before the signing server
mentioned before being able to export UK use.
So obviously to open schema.
So want to be able to take that stuff out and take it any way you want.
Yeah.
It's like that's like the crossover to the protocol one.
And then a protocol side, how do we look at things
like federation between other servers.
So if anyone else wanted to run their own server.
We've talked to some folks in this in the space who kind of were interested
in, like a working group around that sort of thing.
So there's a lot of stuff coming to watch this space,
and then that'll be me.
Okay.
Thank you.
So this is our usual ending slide.
And for that I recycled this image that comes from a 2006 publication.
It's a 20 years old image.
I was doing work on participative systems and CQ is going to be participative.
StackOverflow was and there was this power
law participation that I read about 20 something years ago.
And it shows how like which different type of engagement or participation
you can have with the platform that starts from the lowest effort ones
till the highest effort once, and also the ones that reward you
the more because you contributed the most to a given process.
So the links that we provide here are kind of following the same power law.
So you can just check out our Mozilla organization on GitHub.
There's plenty of projects.
There is something we call the choice first stack for AI development
that starts from agentic frameworks, goes to
routing, goes to
serving or local model serving and adding
guardrails and running encoders, everything like that.
So you will find an open source package for almost everything that you can do here
or try to change. This is super low effort.
You just try the website and see how it works for you.
You can clone the repo and try and play
with the actual code locally and see how that works for you to.
And after you've seen how these things work for you.
Open issues.
We super appreciate harsh comments.
We want to improve.
We want to make this thing something that people actually use. And
to my
desire, if other people want to contribute or want to fork
and have another project which is as open as what we want to build ours.
I just want an open project to to win over here and have these kind of
knowledge units being shared across people and not just owned by a single company.
Submitters, of course, if you want to collaborate with our code
instead of working and yeah, contribute nucleus, that's also, well,
probably not the highest effort thing, but maybe it's something
that you need to put some effort in before you create them
and you test the system on your own.
So I think that is really all from this.
Thanks a lot.
Thank you both so much.
That was really interesting.
And like touching on problems we're talking about every day as well.
We have exactly two minutes for questions.
Does anyone have a question they want to ask quickly? Yes.
Hello there.
How does it work when you have like you're in a big organization,
you have multiple repositories and different domains.
And if you're going to do DDT, you take bounded context or something like this.
Like I saw in the examples, it said like front end and things like this.
How does the retrieval work and all this sort of stuff?
And does it like leak incorrect information
and actually confuse the agent.
So you can try and answer this.
So yeah, it's the skill drives basically like a ton of this stuff
in terms of like it asks the agent to summarize things at us,
the agent to figure out what domains and stuff,
and it also tells it like to try and generalize things
and not to make them specific
to like, like, say like a specific project that it's working on.
Unless that project is like an open source tool,
for example, in that, in which case it would be allowed to.
So the domains, it's the way that it works and sort of thing before
like because it was up and down.
But you kind of like the domains almost like that,
kind of like it's trying to generalize so it can have as many domains as well,
I think, say as many as you said, a list of domains in or things isn't.
Back to my YAML. Yeah.
But you've also got like languages frameworks.
There's a there's a pattern that you can use as like a bespoke string as well.
So like the agent should be told via the skill.
Like a good way to try and use that.
In terms like what stops it from doing stuff
like once things are submitted to like upstream to a remote.
I guess at that point it sort of becomes more of like the guardrail stuff.
And then and then a human in the loop review to say whether something is
or isn't allowed into like the Commons or whatever.
But to add on these,
these, as you clarify, this is very much a retrieval problem, right.
So we have a first implementation.
We also hope we will make this better in time.
So I think there is a lot of effort that can be put here
into making things better and better.
And the more the knowledge base grows,
the more we want to have something that works efficiently.
Yeah, it's actually on that in the open source replayability
to see exactly how the server can work around
how it kind of gets those results
and scores them and then sends back like the the ordered by relevance.
There's a PR one of our colleagues is open
on the open source report to bring in some untick search and stuff.
So exactly that building off that.
Amazing.
Thank you so much guys. Really appreciate that.
Thank you all for coming.
In exactly ten minutes.
We will have our last session before lunch.
Everyone's favorite time slot.
So please come back for that and you can find these guys out and about today.
I hope you can ask them all the questions you like about CQ.
Thanks again. Thanks everybody. Thank you.